<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<data>
  <event start="Jan 01 1875 09:00:00 GMT" isDuration="false" title="Einstein (1875-1955)"/>
  <event start="Jan 01 1802 09:00:00 GMT" isDuration="false" title="Double-slit interference experiment">In quantum mechanics, the double-slit experiment, or double-slit experiment, is an experiment that demonstrates the wave-particle duality of microscopic objects such as photons or electrons. The double-slit experiment is a "double-path experiment". In the double-path experiment, microscopic objects can reach the final point from the starting point through two paths or any one of them at the same time. The phase difference between these two paths causes a phase shift in the quantum state describing the physical behavior of microscopic objects, thereby causing interference phenomena. Another common double-path experiment is the Mach-Zehnder interferometer experiment.</event>
  <event start="Jan 01 1927 09:00:00 GMT" isDuration="false" title="Copenhagen interpretation">The Copenhagen interpretation was mainly proposed by Niels Bohr and Werner Heisenberg when they collaborated in Copenhagen, Denmark in 1927. This interpretation extended the probabilistic representation of the wave function proposed by German mathematician and physicist Max Born, which later developed into the famous uncertainty principle.</event>
  <event start="Jan 01 1869 09:00:00 GMT" isDuration="false" title="Mendeleev made the periodic table">The periodic table of elements is a table that arranges chemical elements according to atomic number, the arrangement of electrons outside the nucleus, and similar chemical properties.</event>
  <event start="Apr 15 1707 09:00:00 GMT" isDuration="false" title="Euler (1707-1783)">A Swiss mathematician and physicist, one of the pioneers of modern mathematics. He made major discoveries in the fields of calculus and graph theory.</event>
  <event start="Jan 01 1873 09:00:00 GMT" isDuration="false" title="Levi Strauss invents jeans">None</event>
  <event start="Jan 01 1887 09:00:00 GMT" isDuration="false" title="Michelson-Morley Experiment">The Michelson-Morley Experiment, conducted in Cleveland, USA in 1887 by Michelson and Morley, is a famous physical experiment measuring the difference in the speed of light in two perpendicular directions using a Michelson interferometer. However, the result proved that the speed of light is the same in different inertial systems and different directions, thereby denying the existence of ether (absolute stationary reference frame), thus shaking the foundation of classical physics, and becoming a beginning of modern physics, occupying a very important position in the history of the development of physics.</event>
</data>
